publicradio.org 2004-10-09

# American Public Media

**Privacy Statement**

You have come to this page from a Web site produced by Minnesota Public Radio (MPR). We recognize the importance of privacy to visitors to any MPR Web site, and we want every user (you) to know how we collect and use information about you when you visit our Web sites. This privacy policy explains what type of information is collected from you when you visit this and other MPR Web sites, and how we may use that information. 

Contents

  * Information we automatically gather when you visit MPR Web sites   

  * Information you give us   

  * About RedSheriff   

  * Name and contact information   

  * Demographic and profile information   

  * Credit-card information   

  * Special note for MPR members   

  * Contact MPR   

  * Consent 

**Information we automatically gather when you visit MPR Web sites**   
Like virtually all other Web servers, MPR's Web server automatically creates log files for each visitor who accesses our site. These "access logs" allow us to make our site more useful to our visitors. The access logs do not record a visitor's name, address, phone number, credit card numbers, or any other personally identifying information. Rather, these log files may contain some or all of the following information: 

  * The date of the visit 
  * The time and length of the visit 
  * The path taken through the Web site 
  * The browser being used 
  * A list of files downloaded or viewed 
  * The amount of time spent listening to audio files 
  * The Internet Protocol Address (IP Address) of the machine accessing our Web site* 
  * Any errors encountered 
  * *Most Internet Service Providers use a "dynamic" form of assigning IP Addresses. This means that a visitor may have a different IP address each time he or she visits an MPR Web site. Also, many Internet Service Providers, including America Online, use "proxy servers," which provide even more anonymity for visitors. 

We use this information to aid the technical administration of the sites and to better understand how each site is functioning for its users. This information may be correlated with your profile, if you have provided this data, to provide special "personalized" services. This information may also be used in aggregate form. 

We may track your visit to sections of our Web sites in order for some site features to function properly for you. In some instances, "cookies" or a similar technology may be used to update your registration records with session information. If you do not wish to accept a cookie from MPR's servers, you can adjust the settings on your browser accordingly. Refusing to accept cookies from the MPR server may result in some limits on the benefits that we can automatically provide as you enjoy the MPR Web sites.

**Information you give us**   
MPR does not collect personally identifying information from MPR Web sites unless you choose to provide that information to us. Visitors under the age of 13 must obtain permission from their parents or guardians before sending any personally identifying information to MPR. 

**Name and contact information**  
MPR may ask visitors (you) to provide certain personal information when you: register for a contest; sign up for an e-mail list; request information; purchase products or services; contribute material that may be used on the Web site (e.g., recipes or program reviews); participate in a discussion board or chat; or use an MPR form to become a member of MPR. You will also have the opportunity to request future e-mail contact from MPR regarding its programs and Web sites. MPR tells you whether a specific piece of information is required at the time it is requested. 

This information may be used by MPR to: verify your identity; manage a contest; gather your editorial comments and feedback; contact you for additional information or administrative purposes; provide attribution for any submitted content of yours published by MPR, and fulfill your order or request. If you opt-in to request future contact from MPR, you may receive e-mail regarding its programs and Web sites; otherwise, MPR will contact you only if necessary for the purposes above.

Unless explicitly stated otherwise at the time of submission, the personally identifying information you provide will not be sold, shared, or used for purposes other than listed above. If MPR does wish to add your information to a shared list, it will do so only if you provide permission when you submit your information-by default, your information will not be added; you must "opt-in."

MPR uses shared lists to maximize the benefits it can provide through its network of public radio Web sites and through qualified associations. If you allow it, your name and basic contact information may be exchanged for consideration with select companies and organizations, including with other public radio stations and programs. These companies and organizations may attempt to contact you to promote a product or service that they offer. Such contacts from third parties will only be made with MPR's consent, and MPR will only grant its consent when MPR considers the offer to be of potential interest and benefit to our Web site users.

MPR will not share, exchange, rent, or sell any of its lists to political parties or candidates for political office.

If you do not want your name and contact information to be used in this way, you may indicate this at the time you provide the information. If you decide after you have provided this information that you do not want MPR to share your information with any company or organization, you may also notify us by e-mailing mail@mpr.org. MPR cannot remove your name from any third party's list; you will have to contact them directly. 

The Direct Marketing Association (DMA) offers a Mail Preference Service that is designed to assist consumers in decreasing the amount of nonprofit or commercial mail they receive at home. For more information about this service, visit the DMA Web site at: www.the-dma.org and click on the "Consumers" tab. 

**Demographic and Personal Information**  
MPR occasionally conducts online surveys, sometimes in association with a contest or other offer. These surveys may ask you for demographic information such as ZIP code, age, education, or income level. Unless otherwise explicitly indicated at the time you provide the information, this information is used in an aggregate form to help us understand our audiences and improve our services. Demographic and profile information may be shared with selected third-party organizations, only on an aggregate basis, to describe the nature of our online audiences. 

**Credit-card information**   
You must be 18 to engage in money-related transactions on an MPR site. When you do so, you will be asked for a credit card number. All financial transactions take place only on secure servers, and electronic communication of credit-card information is sent only in a secured or encrypted format. Your credit card information is saved, in an encrypted format, on internal systems that are either not connected to the Internet or are protected by advanced firewalls separate from the computers that serve MPR public sites. This information is not made available to any third party and is considered completely confidential. 

**Special note for MPR members**  
If you use MPR's secure online form to become a member or make a contribution to MPR, your name, complete contact information, and all contributions will be passed directly to the MPR Membership Department. Your membership information will be protected in full compliance with the MPR Member Lists Policy.

**Contact MPR**  
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or any practices on the MPR sites, please send an e-mail to us at mail@mpr.org or send a letter by regular mail to: Minnesota Public Radio New Media 45 East Seventh Street Saint Paul, MN 55101. MPR reserves the right to change this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted to this page as soon as reasonably possible, so please check this page periodically.

**Consent**  
Your use of the MPR Web site constitutes consent to any policy then in effect.

**RedSheriff**  
The use of RedSheriff's Web site measurement software assists Minnesota Public Radio in analyzing the user experience on our Web sites and improving the structure and ease of use of our Web sites. RedSheriff is used to collect such information as the number of unique visitors, how long visitors spend on our Web sites, and common entry and exit points into and from the Web sites. You cannot be identified personally from this information and no personal information is stored about you.

Further information about RedSheriff, the RedSheriff auditing system and RedSheriff's privacy policy can be found on the RedSheriff Web site
